# Smitkumar Khokhariya

**८** (437)-545-7557 | **≥** skhokhariya22@gmail.com | **in** in/smit-khokhariya | **Q** github.com/smit-sk

## **Professional Summary**

**AWS** certified solution architect and experienced software developer Flutter and C# with a keen interest in cloud technologies specially in containerization and devOps concepts. Demonstrated expertise in software development specially in NodeJS, AWS services, CI/CD pipelines with strong background in ECS and Docker.

### Experience

Vosyn AI Toronto, ON

Cloud Engineer Intern

05/2024 - Present

- Designed and implement the Cloud architecture on AWS for the Auto-dubbing pipeline using Lambda
- Configured and managed **Docker** environments on EC2 instances (**Linux** ami) and registered them with ECS clusters, ensuring efficient orchestration and monitoring of **containerized** applications

UMENIT Solution Noida, India

 $Software\ Developer$ 

11/2021 - 12/2022

- Developed a hospital staff management application using **Flutter Technology**, implemented **BLoC** state management techniques, handled complex and large data across the different states
- Built scalable flower ordering and delivery system using **React Native**, developed reusable modules and UI components adhering to SOLID design principles, ensuring maintainability and scalability
- Integrated **RESTful APIs** and used **data-modal** approach to parse **JSON** data, resulted in a **15**% reduction in data load time and a significant increase in overall user experience

Kylo Apps Delhi, India

Mobile Application Developer

06/2021 - 11/2021

- Worked in a doctor app with integration of **third-party** libraries including Google Maps API, AWS s3, chat functionality, payment gateway, audio-video call services and worked with pdf
- Integrated multiple Firebase services, including Google and email/password authentication, real-time database for live updates, and cloud storage to stored media files
- Utilized various state management techniques, such as Redux for React Native and, Provider and MobX for Flutter, within an MVVM design pattern to enhance app performance and maintain CLEAN code architecture
- Led the deployment process to **App Store** and **Play Store** for mobile applications

## **Technical Skills**

Languages : C#, Dart, JavaScript, Typescript, Python, SQL

Frameworks : Flutter, React Native, Node.js, Flask

Database : Firebase, Cloud Firestore, SQLite, MongoDB

Tools : Visual Studio Code, Version Control - Github, AWS, Azure, Terraform

Certification : AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, AWS Certified Solution Architect - associate

Other skills : Knowledge of Object Oriented Programming, understanding of devOps concepts, problem-solving

skills, teamwork, communication, self-motivated

#### **Projects**

AI Image Generator | flutter, dart, getx, firebase

06/2024 – present

- Developed an AI Image generator flutter mobile application with integration of REST APIs
- Utilized firebase database to manage backend operation such as API's data

**H2O Helper** | React Native, Expo, JavaScript, Redux, Push Notification

12/2023 - 02/2024

- Created a react native Water Hydration Reminder app, enabling users to set personalized daily water goal, water intake logging, and providing insightful analysis of daily progress by storing water data in local database
- Implemented features like hydration reminders by push notification, visual progress unit of measure customization, hydration tips and app theme customization, integrated **Redux** for handling data over app effectively

#### Education

Fanshawe College

01/2023 - 04/2024

Post Graduation in Mobile Application Development (GPA - 3.97/4.20)

London, ON

Charotar University of Science and Technology

06/2018 - 05/2022

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology (GPA - 3.72/4.20)

Gujarat, India